export const topick8 = [
  {
    question:
      'What structure was built to improve shipping in Ostend in the 18th century?',
    options: {
      a: 'Canal',
      b: 'Bridge',
      c: 'Dam',
    },
    answer: 'Canal',
  },
  {
    question: 'In what year was the first canal in Ostend built?',
    options: {
      a: '1604',
      b: '1722',
      c: '1830',
    },
    answer: '1722',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What structure was built to protect the port of Ostend in the 19th century?',
    options: {
      a: "Napoleon's Fortress",
      b: 'Defense Dam',
      c: 'Sea Wall',
    },
    answer: 'Defense Dam',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What important sea route passed through Ostend in the 18th century?',
    options: {
      a: 'Route to India',
      b: 'Route to America',
      c: 'Route to Africa',
    },
    answer: 'Route to India',
  },
  {
    question: 'What structure was built in Ostend to improve navigation?',
    options: {
      a: 'Lighthouse',
      b: 'Tower',
      c: 'Dam',
    },
    answer: 'Lighthouse',
  },
  {
    question: 'In what year was the new port of Ostend built?',
    options: {
      a: '1604',
      b: '1722',
      c: '1838',
    },
    answer: '1838',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What type of transport was the main one for the transportation of goods in Ostend in the 18th century?',
    options: {
      a: 'Railroad',
      b: 'Maritime transport',
      c: 'Road transport',
    },
    answer: 'Maritime transport',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What structure was built to protect the port of Ostend from floods?',
    options: {
      a: 'Defense Dam',
      b: 'Sea Wall',
      c: 'Canal',
    },
    answer: 'Defense Dam',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What structure was built to increase the capacity of the port of Ostend?',
    options: {
      a: 'New dock',
      b: 'New bridge',
      c: 'New dam',
    },
    answer: 'New dock',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What structure was built in Ostend to improve communication with other ports?',
    options: {
      a: 'Bridge',
      b: 'Canal',
      c: 'Dam',
    },
    answer: 'Canal',
  },
];
